<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>The Wall Lab</title>
		<description>Wall Lab at Stanford School of Medicine</description>
		<link>https://wall-lab.stanford.edu</link>
		<atom:link href="https://wall-lab.stanford.edu/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Congratulations Catalin!</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford graduate student and Google Glass team member, Catalin Voss was one of only a small handful of students awarded the 2016 Lemelson-MIT Student Prize for his work with Google Glass. His award and past successes are featured in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scientificamerican.com/article/autism-glass-takes-top-student-health-tech-prize-slide-show1/&quot;&gt;an article by Scientific American&lt;/a&gt;. Please join us in saying contratulations to this increadible acheivement!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>https://wall-lab.stanford.edu/2016/04/14/congratulations-catalin!/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://wall-lab.stanford.edu/2016/04/14/congratulations-catalin!/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Kqed Science Interviews Wall Lab On Autism Glass Project</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;The Autism Google Glass team and a participant in Phase II sat down with KQED journalist, Lindsey Hoshaw, to be featured in an &lt;a href=&quot;http://ww2.kqed.org/futureofyou/2016/04/08/google-glass-flopped-but-kids-with-autism-are-using-it-to-learn-emotions/?utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;utm_medium=socialmedia&amp;amp;utm_campaign=kqedmain&quot;&gt;article published by KQED Science&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;quot;Google Glass flopped. But kids with autism are using it to learn emotions.&amp;quot; The article not only highlights work done by the glass team, but provides important attention to one of the projects participants, and how the device has helped her socialize with family and friends. The team is excited to get the word out about what google glass can do not only for participants in the study, but to more children with ASD who could benefit from the device. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>https://wall-lab.stanford.edu/2016/04/13/kqed-science-interviews-wall-lab-on-autism-glass-project/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://wall-lab.stanford.edu/2016/04/13/kqed-science-interviews-wall-lab-on-autism-glass-project/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Congratulations To Autism Google Glass Team For Best Poster Award</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;In early March, Autism Google Glass team members Nick Haber and Catalin Voss attended Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers&amp;#39; Winter conference on Applications of Computer Vision in Lake Placid, New York. While there, they presented a poster for their paper &amp;quot;A practical approach to real-time neutral feature subtraction for facial expression recognition&amp;quot; and won Best Poster Award. The paper focuses on improving social interactions for children with autism through the use of wearable glasses that give real-time social cues to the wearer. The device can record the type of and amount of eye contact recorded from the wearer, which can be a critical component of behavioral therapy. The study in which the glasses are used involves 100 participants from ages 6-16. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>https://wall-lab.stanford.edu/2016/04/13/congratulations-to-autism-google-glass-team-for-best-poster-award/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://wall-lab.stanford.edu/2016/04/13/congratulations-to-autism-google-glass-team-for-best-poster-award/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Dennis Wall Talks Big Data Approaches To Autism Research</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Erin Digitale of Stanford Medicine News sat down with Dr. Wall to discuss the advancements in Autism research and diagnosis. He goes into roadblocks many families face today, what diagnostic tools and methods have looked like in the past, big-data computations, and the innovative ways they are restructuring the screening tests to identify developmental disorders earlier and quicker. Read &lt;a href=&quot;http://scopeblog.stanford.edu/2016/02/23/new-stanford-research-offers-hope-for-faster-autism-diagnosis/on&quot;&gt;more&lt;/a&gt; how Dr. Wall and his team are using technology and mathematics to make diagnosis of Autism and other developmental disorders faster, easier, and more accurate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>https://wall-lab.stanford.edu/2016/03/07/dennis-wall-talks-big-data-approaches-to-autism-research/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://wall-lab.stanford.edu/2016/03/07/dennis-wall-talks-big-data-approaches-to-autism-research/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Congratulations To Dr. Wall And His Team!</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;The Hartwell Foundation’s Autism Research and Technology Initiative (iHART) hopes to empower the global scientific research community with open access to a centralized repository of autism data with the potential to benefit children. We are so excited for iHART and can&amp;#39;t wait to see what it accomplishes! View the article &lt;a href=&quot;https://med.stanford.edu/news/all-news/2015/06/9-million-grant-to-establish-open-access-autism-database.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>https://wall-lab.stanford.edu/2015/06/17/congratulations-to-Dr.-Wall-and-his-team!/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://wall-lab.stanford.edu/2015/06/17/congratulations-to-Dr.-Wall-and-his-team!/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Stanford Winter Mini-Course Personalized Genomic Medicine</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. Wall is to teach a Stanford Winter mini-course, Personalized Genomic Medicine, BIOS 234. Follow this &lt;a href=&quot;http://stanford.edu/class/bios2354&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This course will provide an introduction to NGS and its implications for personalized genomic medicine. Students will gain hands-on experience with popular DNA sequence analysis tools as well as a practical understanding of the underlying algorithms and biomedicine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>https://wall-lab.stanford.edu/2015/03/04/stanford-mini-course-personalized-genomic-medicine/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://wall-lab.stanford.edu/2015/03/04/stanford-mini-course-personalized-genomic-medicine/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>We're Looking for a Bioinformatics Specialist</title>
				<description>&lt;h3&gt;Job description&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The laboratory of Dr. Dennis Wall at Stanford School of Medicine is seeking highly motivated staff to develop and study novel approaches in data-driven biomedical research to discover new biomarkers, therapeutics, and to revolutionize health and health-care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Primary Purpose(s)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employee will conduct research and development in biomedical informatics and biostatistics, by architecting, developing, maintaining, and documenting a bioinformatics software infrastructure that integrates disparate forms of clinical and genomic data and offers other evolving capabilities to support research activities.  Responsibilities for this position include... &lt;a href=&quot;http://wall-lab.stanford.edu/jobs/#senior-bioinformatician&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>https://wall-lab.stanford.edu/2015/01/22/looking-for-bioinformatics-specialist/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://wall-lab.stanford.edu/2015/01/22/looking-for-bioinformatics-specialist/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Stanford Medicine Notable People January 2015</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;For the Wall Lab&amp;#39;s work in machine learning and developing systems methods to reduce the time needed to screen, detect, treat, and track patients with Autism Spectrum Disorder, Dr. Wall has been listed as one of Stanford Medicine&amp;#39;s Notable People this month. 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://med.stanford.edu/news/all-news/brands/notable.html&quot;&gt;Read more.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>https://wall-lab.stanford.edu/2015/01/16/stanford-medicine-notable-people-jan-2015/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://wall-lab.stanford.edu/2015/01/16/stanford-medicine-notable-people-jan-2015/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Soaring Demands for Autism Treatment</title>
				<description>Autism Spectrum Disorder has gotten the attention of companies with the soaring demand for diagnostic tools and treatments to help those with the disorders and those around them as much as possible. According to the article, one in 68 children is autistic. Dr. Wall is mentioned for his work with Cognoa and it&#39;s 90% success rate. 

[Read more at the Economist](http://www.economist.com/news/business/21636064-companies-struggle-meet-soaring-demand-autism-treatments-development)
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>https://wall-lab.stanford.edu/2014/12/16/meet-soaring-demand-autism-treatments-development/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://wall-lab.stanford.edu/2014/12/16/meet-soaring-demand-autism-treatments-development/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Leticia Heads Back to Spain (Again)</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Our resident Spaniard and Route66 lead, Leticia, has returned to Spain again to work remotely with the lab. See you at lab meetings!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>https://wall-lab.stanford.edu/2014/11/22/leticia-heads-back-to-spain-again/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://wall-lab.stanford.edu/2014/11/22/leticia-heads-back-to-spain-again/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
